Guide to the John H. Eyer Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
John H. Eyer papers
1930-1986
1950-1974
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
3932
Eyer, John H.,$d -1986
18.45 cubic feet (17 boxes) plus 1 oversize folder
Papers of John H. Eyer, organizer, international representative, and training specialist for the International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite and Paper Mill Workers from circa 1951-1964 and International Representative and Job Analysis Program Chair of the Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers beginning in 1964.
Professional:
John H. Eyer (1906-1986) was an organizer, international representative and training specialist based in Portland, Oregon, for the International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite and Paper Mill Workers (IBPSandPMW) from about 1951-1964. Eyer became training specialist in 1956 which emerged into a permanent position as Representative of the International’s West Coast Research and Education Department in 1957, traveling frequently to locals across the West Coast. Part of this work also included the performance of job analyses, evaluating wages and contracts of locals within the union. At this time, he became a confidant of Research and Education head, George W. Brooks, who figured prominently in the internal campaign for reform, and whose forced resignation in 1961 precipitated the formation of the Rank and File Movement for Democratic Action (RFMDA). An organization created by dissatisfied members of the International, the RFMDA had participation from members of paper worker locals across the United States and even parts of Canada. This reform movement was the catalyst for the formation of new union, the Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers (AWPPW) in 1964. Along with many members in favor of the reform, John Eyer moved over to the rebel union, AWPPW, becoming an International Representative and chairing its Job Analysis Program. He also served as General Vice President of the AWPPW in the late 1960s. In addition to union involvement, he was also active in the City Club of Portland and served on the Executive Boards of the American Civil Liberties Union of Oregon and the World Without War Council of Portland.
Personal:
John Howard Eyer was born August 28, 1906 to Mildred Neal and Wilson Eyer. John also had an older brother named Lowell. In June 1930, he married Alice Meisel. John and Alice gave birth to daughter Janet Helen Eyer, who later gave birth to his granddaughter, Susan. Alice Eyer passed away in 1969. John Eyer married again sometime in the 1970s to Rosa Millo, Recording Secretary of AWPPW Local 644 in Everett, Washington and Secretary-Treasurer of the AWPPW Northern Washington and Alaska Area Council. John Eyer passed away in 1986.
Organized into 2 accessions.
Accession No. 3932-001, John H. Eyer papers, 1930-1986
Accession No. 3932-002, John H. Eyer papers, 1967-1969
Correspondence, negotiation files, agreements, subject files, newsletters, court papers, and other material, relating to Eyer's activities as international representative of International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite, and Paper Mill Workers, based in Portland, Or., organizer at mills in the Pacific Northwest during the 1950s, and his later work in the union's Research and Education Dept., where he was in charge on the West Coast. Papers also document the reform movement in the union, including the controversy over the forced resignation of George W. Brooks, head of Research and Education Dept., 1961, resulting in formation of Rank and File Movement for Democratic Action within the union, revolt of West Coast locals and formation of West Coast Pulp and Paper Workers, 1964, in which Eyer served as general vice-president from 1965-1968. Includes files of Burt D. Wells, secretary/treasurer of Rank and File Movement for Democratic Action, and other leaders. Major correspondent is John P. Burke.
Forms part of the Labor Archives of Washington.
Collection is open for research but records stored offsite; advance notice is required for use.
Due to the following collections' distinctiveness as bodies of records belonging to Burt D. Wells and Rosa M. Eyer respectively, and the materials' historical significance, these collections were separated from the first accession of the John H. Eyer papers during processing in December 2017.
Burt D. Wells papers (Collection No. 6176)
Rosa M. Eyer papers (Collection No. 6178)
Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers records (Collection No. 2052)
Labor education$zUnited States; Labor unions$xRecognition; Wood-pulp industry workers$xLabor unions; Labor disputes$zPacific States; Paper industry workers$xLabor unions$zNorthwest, Pacific; Labor unions$xOrganizing; Pulpwood industry$zUnited States; Brooks, George W.; Burke, John P.$vCorrespondence; Eyer, John H.,$d -1986$vArchives; Wells, Burton D.; Perrin, William; Sherman, John; Swanson, John R.; Hannigan, Francis; Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers; International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite, and Paper Mill Workers; International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite, and Paper Mill Workers.$bDepartment of Research and Education; Newsletters; Labor leaders$zWashington (State); Rank and File Movement for Democratic Action; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); City Club of Portland (Portland, Or.); Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor History; Labor Unions; Logging; Oregon; Portland
- John H. Eyer papers, 1930-1986; 1950-1974; 3932-001; 18.24 cubic feet (16 boxes) plus 1 oversize folder
  This accession spans the years 1930-1986 and consist primarily of records created or compiled by John Eyer during his work as an educator and representative for the International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite and Paper Mill Workers and the Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers. Some material related to the United Papermakers and Paperworkers union is also included. These records feature John Eyer’s involvement with a variety of paper worker locals across the West Coast, from British Columbia to Southern California, including the performance of job analyses, as well as union local and parent organization engagement with major paper companies, such as Weyerhaeuser, Crown Simpson, and Georgia-Pacific. This accession also highlights tensions between the International and its membership where a faction of members formed the Rank and File Movement for Democratic Action (RFMDA) which emerged into rebel union, Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers in 1964. Also included is a small series of personal papers of Eyer’s consisting of records related to his non-union organizational involvement, family correspondence and birth and death records, and information on Oregon state and national politics.
  Materials consist of a large quantity of correspondence to and from Eyer and other International and AWPPW officers and rank and file members, as well as reports; meeting minutes; grievance and arbitration files; contract agreements and constitutions; flyers, pamphlets, and other ephemera; Eyer's handwritten notes and article drafts; news clippings, newsletters, and full newspaper publications, primarily that published by paper worker locals; and several photographs (maintained in their original arrangement and noted in the collection inventory). Subject matter includes strikes; contract negotiations and collective bargaining, including the Uniform Labor Agreement; wages, including union attempts to address the gender pay gap; health insurance, pensions, and other benefits; job analyses of union locals; education and union training programs; arbitration and grievances; paper mill water pollution; election of officers; and elections for union representation.
  Note- there is considerable overlap and potential duplication of material across the series in this accession but are maintained in their original arrangement in order to preserve the varied reasons why and how these records were kept. For more detailed description of each series, please see the collection inventory below.
  Collection is open for research but records stored offsite; advance notice is required for use
  Donated by Rosa Millo Eyer, September 14, 1987.
  The collection is arranged into the following series:
  SERIES 1: PAPER WORKER UNION LOCALS
  SERIES 2: INTERNATIONAL BROTHERHOOD OF PULP, SULPHITE AND PAPER MILL WORKERS
  Subseries A: Officer Correspondence
  Subseries B: Meetings and Conventions
  Subseries C: Secretary Francis Hannigan, Local 242 (Portland, OR)
  Subseries D: Vice President John Sherman
  Subseries E: Other Records
  SERIES 3: ASSOCIATION OF WESTERN PULP AND PAPER WORKERS
  Subseries A: Correspondence and Reports
  Subseries B: Collective Bargaining
  Subseries C: Regional Councils
  Subseries D: Conventions
  Subseries E: Representative John R. Swanson, Northern Washington and Alaska Area Council
  Subseries F: Other Records
  SERIES 4: UNITED PAPERMAKERS AND PAPERWORKERS
  SERIES 5: UNIFORM LABOR AGREEMENT
  SERIES 6: PAPER WORKER ORGANIZATIONS AND COUNCILS
  SERIES 7: JOB ANALYSIS AND TRAINING
  SERIES 8: PAPER COMPANIES
  Subseries A: Boise Cascade
  Subseries B: Crown Simpson
  Subseries C: Crown Zellerbach
  Subseries D: ITT Rayonier
  Subseries E: Kimberly-Clark
  Subseries F: Scott
  Subseries G: Simpson Lee
  Subseries H: Weyerhaeuser
  Subseries I: Other Companies
  Subseries J: Pensions
  Subseries K: Arbitration
  SERIES 9: LEGAL CASE FILES
  SERIES 10: SUBJECT FILES
  Subseries A: Labor
  Subseries B: Water Pollution
  SERIES 11: PERSONAL PAPERS
  Subseries A: Other Organizational Involvement
  Subseries B: Family
  Subseries C: Subject Files: State and National Politics
  - PAPER WORKER UNION LOCALS, 1943-1972; SERIES 1 (Box-folder 1/1-5/18, Oversize folder 1)
    Contains assorted records, arranged in alphabetical order by city, from individual paper worker union locals along the West Coast. Locals are primarily affiliated with the International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite and Paper Mill Workers; however, the United Papermakers and Paperworkers and Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers are also represented in this series.
    - Arcata, California, Humbolt Local 67: Elected Officers, Negotiations, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Coos Bay, Oregon, Local 232: Closing of Local, Training, Taft-Hartley, Uniform Labor Agreement, 1957-1964 (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Corvallis, Oregon, Evans Products Company and Local 824: Negotiations, 1964 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Cosmopolis, Washington, Local 211: Grievances, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Cosmopolis, Washington, Local 211 and 861: Collective Bargaining, Job Analysis, Grievances and Arbitration, 1957-1972 (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Duncan Bay, Local 742: Union Training, 1958 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Emeryville, California, Local 255: Constitution and Bylaws, 1960 August 25 (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Everett, Washington, Locals 10, 20, 272, 183, and 644: Negotiations, Strike, 1964 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Everett, Washington, Locals 272, 860, and 236, 1951-1967; Contains issue of The Labor Journal, April 23, 1958 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Forest Grove, Oregon, Forest Fibre Local 687, 1951-1966 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Forest Grove, Oregon, Forest Fibre Products Company and Local 687: Contract Negotiations, Pensions, 1957-1966; Contains issue of International Woodworker, June 26, 1963 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Forest Grove, Oregon, Forest Fibre Paper Products Company and Local 687: Contract Negotiations, 1969 (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Flint, Michigan, Local 578: Rudy Samic, Strike, 1958-1966 (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Fresno, California, Local 930: Contract Negotiations, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Gardiner Oregon, Local 101 and 686, 1964-1971 (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Halsey, Oregon, Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers Organizing, 1969 (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Dee, Oregon, International Woodworkers Association Local 5-18 and Hood River, Oregon, International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite and Paper Mill Workers Local 732, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 1/17)
    - Ketchikan, Alaska, Pulp Company: Welfare Plans, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Ketchikan, Alaska, Ketchikan Pulp Company: Photographs of 4th of July Parade Float and Pulp Employees King Salmon Derby Prize Winners, 1957 (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Ketchikan, Alaska, Local 783: Assorted Photographs of John Eyer and Local Members, circa 1954-1960 (Box-folder 1/20)
    - Ketchikan, Alaska, Local 783: Union Training, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 1/21)
    - Ketchikan, Alaska: Employment Security and Unemployment Compensation, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 1/22)
    - Ketchikan, Alaska, Local 783: Cooperative Store, 1963 (Box-folder 1/23)
    - Ketchikan Pulp Company Recognition of Local 783 as Union, 1952-1954 (Box-folder 1/24)
    - Ketchikan, Alaska, Ketchikan Pulp Company and Local 783: Negotiations, 1943-1954; Folder 25 Contains issue of Pulp, Sulphite, and Paper Workers Journal, May-June 1943 (Box-folder 1/25-26)
    - Ketchikan, Alaska, Local 783: Ketchikan Pulp Company and International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite and Paper Mill Workers Negotiation Meeting Minutes, 1958 (Box-folder 1/27)
    - Ketchikan, Alaska, Ketchikan Pulp Company and Local 783: Negotiation Meeting Minutes and Agreements, 1959 (Box-folder 1/28)
    - Ketchikan, Alaska, Local 783: Ketchikan Pulp Company Negotiations and Strike, 1959 (Box-folder 1/29)
    - Ketchikan, Alaska, Local 783: Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers vs International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite and Paper Mill Workers Election, 1964 (Box-folder 1/30)
    - Ketchikan, Alaska, Ketchikan Pulp Company and Local 783: Negotiations and Agreements, 1964 (Box-folder 1/31-32)
    - Ketchikan, Alaska, Ketchikan Pulp Company and Local 783: Negotiations and Other Records, 1954-1967 (Box-folder 1/33-36, 2/1)
    - Ketchikan, Alaska, Ketchikan Pulp Company and Local 783: John Eyer's Negotiation Notes, circa 1956-1959 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Ketchikan, Alaska, Ketchikan Pulp Company and Local 783: News Clippings, 1956 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Ketchikan, Alaska, Ketchikan Pulp Company and Local 783: Raids and National Labor Relations Board Case, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Ketchikan, Alaska, Ketchikan Pulp Company and Local 783: Negotiations, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Oversized Signs, Flyers, and Publications, 1956-1970 (Folder:oversize 1)
      - Sign Advertising Special Meeting of Local 783, Ketchikan, Alaska on Company Offer, circa 1956
    - Klamath Falls, Oregon, Johns-Manville Plant: Operating Engineers Strike, African American and Native American Workers, 1953-1958; Contains three photographs of plant in Klamath Falls, possibly the Johns-Manville Plant. (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Lebanon, Oregon, Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers Local 214, 1957-1969 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Lewiston, Idaho and Potlatch Forests, Incirca Locals 712 and 608, 1952-1967 (Box-folder 2/8-9)
    - Longview, Washington Locals 153, 633, 580, and 680, 1967-1976 (Box-folder 2/10)
    - Longview, Washington Local 153, 1959-1967; Contains issues of Local 153 newsletter, The Broke Beater (Box-folder 2/11-12)
    - Longview Fibre Company and Local 153: Contract Negotiations, 1969 (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Longview, Washington Locals 153 and 580: Job Analysis, Disaffiliation with International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite and Paper Mill Workers, and Grievances, 1957-1968 (Box-folder 2/14)
    - Longview, Washington Locals 153, 633, and 580: Arbitration, Officer Elections, New Union Hall, 1954-1967; Contains issues of Paper Worker and The Rebel (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Longview Fibre Company and International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite and Paper Mill Workers Arbitration, 1961 (Box-folder 2/16)
    - Longview, Washington and Weyerhaeuser Plant Local 580, 1958-1964; Contains issues of Paper Worker and photographs of Local 580 members, including Local President Millard J. Lamb. (Box-folder 2/17)
    - Longview, Washington Local 580: Employee Disciplinary Action, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Longview, Washington, R-W Paper Company and Local 680: Collective Bargaining, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 2/19)
    - Los Angeles, California, Crown Zellerbach Plant Local 266, 1958-1970 (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Los Angeles, California, Longview Fibre Company Locals 6 and 680: Agreement, Training Classes, 1957-1964, 1969 (Box-folder 2/21)
    - Medford, Oregon, Minnesota Mining and Manufacturing Company Plant: Pulp Workers Petition Correspondence, 1967 August 1 (Box-folder 2/22)
    - Millwood, Washington, Local 218: Inland Empire Paper Company Pension Plan, Financial Report, 1957-1964 (Box-folder 2/23)
    - Modesto, California, Marathon Corporation Local 224: Printing Pressmen Disputes, 1957-1967 (Box-folder 2/24)
    - Newark, California Locals 819 and 846: Training Classes, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 2/25)
    - Newberg, Oregon, Spaulding Pulp and Paper Company and Local 358: Contract Negotiations, Coos Bay Local 232, 1952-1964 (Box-folder 2/26)
    - Newberg, Oregon, Publisher's Paper Company: International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite and Paper Mill Workers vs. Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers Vote, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 2/27)
    - Newberg, Oregon, Spaulding Pulp and Paper Company and Local 358: Contract Negotiations and Pensions, 1956-1964 (Box-folder 2/28)
    - North Bend, Oregon, Menasha Corporation and Sand Dunes Local 1000: Disciplinary Action and Arbitration, 1963-1971 (Box-folder 2/29)
    - Ocean Falls, British Columbia, Local 312, 1958-1964; Contains Crown Zellerbach Canada newsletter, A Management Report, and issue of Western Pulp and Paper Worker (Box-folder 2/30)
    - Oregon City and West Linn, Oregon, Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers Locals 68 and 166: Arbitration, 1959-1971; Includes records related to arbitration case of two Local 68 members tried for attempting to sway members away from the Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers to join the International. (Box-folder 2/31-32)
    - Oregon City, Oregon, Local 68, 1951-1964; Contains letter documenting John Eyer's move from the International to the Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers as well as an issue of Paper Worker (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Oregon City, Oregon, Local 68: Grievance and Arbitration Case, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Pilot Rock, Oregon, U.S. Gypsum Plant Organizing, 1953-1965 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Pittsburg, California, John Mansville Plant Organizing, 1966 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Pomona, California, Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers Local 318, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Portland, Oregon, Local 64 and Rose City Local 242, 1948-1972; Contains issue of Portland-based Fibreboard Imprint magazine and November 1965 issue of Paper Worker (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Portland, Oregon, Fibreboard Paper Products Employee Benefits, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Portland, Oregon, Rose City Local 242: Seniority and Officer Elections, Grievances, and Job Analysis, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Portland, Oregon, Rose City Local 242: Bylaw Amendment Resolutions, 1959-1964 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Portland, Oregon, Lloyd A. Fry Roofing Company: Union Membership Organizing, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Portland, Oregon, Fibreboard Paper Products and Local 242: Lithographic Department, Job Analysis, 1951-1963 (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Portland, Oregon, Fibreboard Paper Products: Employee Military Leave Paperwork, 1951-1959 (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Portland, Oregon, Package Containers, Inc. and Local 242 Organizing, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Portland, Oregon and Stockton, California, Fibreboard Paper Products: Lithographers Move to Amalgamated Lithographers of America, 1957-1962; Includes documentation related to the National Labor Relations Board election for the lithographers to become a part of the Amalgamated Lithographers of America instead of being a part of paper workers unions. (Box-folder 3/14)
    - Portland, Oregon, Rose City Local 242: Meeting Minutes, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 3/15)
    - Portland, Oregon, Fibreboard Paper Products Company and Local 242: Union Standing Committee Meeting Minutes and Correspondence, 1947-1961 (Box-folder 3/16)
    - Portland, Oregon, Rose City Local 242: Assorted Correspondence, 1956-1963 (Box-folder 3/17)
    - Port Alberni, British Columbia, Local 592: Correspondence Regarding British Columbia Standard Labor Agreement and Pension Plan, 1960 September 7 (Box-folder 3/18)
    - Port Angeles, Washington, Local 155: Company Disputes, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 3/19)
    - Port Angeles Mechanics Program: Negotiations and Arbitration, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 3/20)
    - Powell River, British Columbia, Local 76: Training, Retirement, U.S. Social Security Program, 1960 (Box-folder 3/21)
    - Prince Rupert, British Columbia, Watson Island Local 708: Accident and Health Plan, Training Classes, 1958-1963 (Box-folder 3/22)
    - Ripon, California, Simpson Lee Paper Company and Local 683: Arbitration Regarding Vacation Time, 1968 December 11 (Box-folder 3/23)
    - Red Bluff, California, Local 876: Union Training Program, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 3/24)
    - St. Helens, Oregon, Local 166: Sawdust Unloader Dispute, Officer Installation, 1955-1968 (Box-folder 3/25)
    - St. Helens, Oregon, Boise Cascade Corporation St. Helens Mill and Local 1: Agreement, Workman's Compensation Bill, 1969 (Box-folder 3/26)
    - Salem, Oregon, Boise Cascade Company and Local 467: Bargaining Offer, Flyer, 1969 (Box-folder 3/27)
    - Salem, Oregon, Local 467: Boise Cascade Company Strike, Retirement Training, 1957-1968 (Box-folder 3/28)
    - Salem, Oregon, Local 247: Negotiations, Agreements, Elections, 1954-1967 (Box-folder 3/29)
    - Samoa, California, Samoa Report Newsletter: International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite and Paper Mill Workers, American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations, and Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers Election, 1966 April 4 (Box-folder 3/30)
    - Samoa, California, Samoa Pulp Mill, Georgia-Pacific Mill, Local 49: Picketing, Bargaining, National Labor Relations Board Election, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 3/31)
    - Samoa, California, Georgia-Pacific Pulp Mill Organizing: Craft Mill Separation, Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers vs International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite and Paper Mill Workers National Labor Relations Board Election, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 3/32)
    - San Jose, California, Local 868: Insurance, Negotiations, and Union Training, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 3/33)
    - Santa Clara, California, Local 657: Officer Roster, Job Analysis, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 3/34)
    - Sante Fe Springs, California, American Forest Products Corporation and Local 961: Report of Negotiations, 1959 October 15 (Box-folder 3/35)
    - Seattle, Washington, St. Regis Paper Company and Printing Specialties and Paper Products Unions Local 380 Agreement, 1950 July (Box-folder 3/36)
    - Seattle, Washington, Local 817, 1955-1972 (Box-folder 3/37)
    - Seattle, Washington, Longview Fibre Company and Local 817: Elections, Officers, Arbitration, New Equipment, 1965-1972 (Box-folder 3/38)
    - Seattle, Washington, Longview Fibre Company and Local 817: Agreement Drafts with Notes, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 3/39)
    - Shelton, Washington, Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers vs ITT Rayonier Incorporated: Equal Opportunity Employment Commission and Gender and Pay Discrimination Case, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 3/40)
    - Shelton, Washington, ITT Rayonier Corporation and Local 161: Bargaining Agenda, Arbitration, Job Analysis, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 3/41)
    - Shelton, Washington, ITT Rayonier Corporation and Local 161: Arbitration Regarding Employee Dismissal Case, 1967 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Shelton, Washington, Local 161: Grievances, Meeting Reports, Job Analysis, Finances, 1957-1971 (Box-folder 4/2)